const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",o="civiledu",i=200,t=120,a=[{id:91,question:"The headquarters of ECOWAS is located in",option:{a:"Abuja",b:"Accra",c:"Adis-Ababa",d:"Lome"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:17,question:"In Nigeria, public servants are expected to be",option:{a:"non - partisan",b:"political",c:"ambitious",d:"apolitical"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:234,question:"The organ of government which are normally fused in a military regime are the",option:{a:"judiciary and legislative",b:"civil service and executive",c:"legislative and executive",d:"legislative and judiciary"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:48,question:"The upper legislative chamber of the National Assembly of Nigeria is also known as the",option:{a:"honourables",b:"house of commons.",c:"house of lords",d:"senate"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:97,question:"The channel through which political parties make their program known to the people is ..............",option:{a:"canvassing",b:"campaigning",c:"convincing",d:"coronation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:407,question:"Cultism in tertiary institutions in Nigeria was originally introduced to",option:{a:"perpetuate the use of local gin and alcohol",b:"harass opponents of university administrators",c:"fight colonialism and oppressive rules",d:"promote inter-communal marriages."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:271,question:"Mr Dickson’s little son, clement was sent away from school because he has not paid his school fees of 	N=11,000. That same day as Mr Dickson boarded a Danfo bus he noticed that the purse of a fellow passenger dropped on the floor of the bus. Mr Dickson tactically picked up the purse, opened it and saw a handsome sum of N=100,000. No body in the bus noticed him, neither did the fellow passenger. As a patriotic and good citizen of Nigeria, what is Mr Dickson expected to do",option:{a:"Pay his tithe (1/10 of the money) to the church take the rest and pray for forgiveness",b:"Draw the attention of the fellow passenger and give the money back to him /her",c:"Use part of the money to pay his son’s fess and keep the rest because opportunity comes but once",d:"Leave the purse on the floor, and mind his business"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:177,question:"A government is said to be legitimate if it",option:{a:"has the people’s mandate to rule",b:"is not oppressive",c:"provide social services for the people",d:"accepts people’s criticism"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:232,question:"Public corporation are owned by the",option:{a:"government",b:"banks",c:"private individuals",d:"foreigners"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:21,question:"What value did Imoh demonstrate.",option:{a:"Tolerance",b:"Confidence",c:"Fair play",d:"Honesty"},section:"Imoh lived with her parents in Kakuri. They were good citizens who detested all forms of immoral acts. Both at home and in school, Imoh had been taught the virtues and values of a good citizen. However, while in a bus on her way home from school, the conductor forgot to ask for her fare. She knew that the right thing to do was to pay even when the conductor had forgotten to collect the fare. She also knew that there were other things she could do with the money if it was not paid, but she did what was expected by informing the conductor and paying the fare.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:198,question:"The primary duty of the police force is to",option:{a:"Make law",b:"Interpret the law",c:"Deal with danfo and okada drivers",d:"Non of the above"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:52,question:"The following are values that promote interpersonal relationship, except",option:{a:"caring.",b:"honesty.",c:"patience",d:"properties."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:327,question:"A Taxi diver who mistakenly Jams and kills someone is guilty of ............... and he will receive ................ punishment than if it were a case of ........",option:{a:"murder, less, manslaughter",b:"man slaughter, less, murder",c:"manslaughter, more, murder",d:"civil offence, less, murder"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:340,question:"Decrees are laws made by .............",option:{a:"the parliament",b:"the judiciary",c:"the military",d:"senators"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:239,question:"Cultism is ........, and so it should be ........",option:{a:"useful - allowed",b:"cultural - encouraged",c:"dangerous - discouraged",d:"amiable - supported"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:201,question:"Some core Rights or Freedoms in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights of 1948 are",option:{a:"The right to life and right to freedom of opinion and expression",b:"The right to fight and smoke in the public place",c:"The right to attack your enemies and the right to make slanderous speeches",d:"None of the above"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:246,question:"Juvenile delinquency and cultism are ......... and should be .........",option:{a:"undesirable - encouraged",b:"desirable - discouraged",c:"undesirable - discouraged",d:"desirable - discouraged"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:377,question:"Which of the following is not a way of improving public service?",option:{a:"Politicization",b:"Refresher courses",c:"The use of Code Conduct Bureau",d:"Reformation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:402,question:"Human rights are described as inviolable mainly because they are",option:{a:"authoritative declaration",b:"enforceable everywhere",c:"not to be unnecessarily taken away",d:"legal declaration instruments"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:349,question:"Which of the following instruments is not used by a civil society group?",option:{a:"Propaganda",b:"Boycott",c:"Protest",d:"Violence"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:215,question:"Which of the following can cause Human Trafficking in a country",option:{a:"poverty, youth unemployment and greed",b:"Sound education and proper counselling",c:"Social and economic contentment",d:"B and C above"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:63,question:"How many members constitute the lower legislative chamber in Nigeria?",option:{a:"300",b:"302",c:"312",d:"360"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:125,question:"The following are causes of emergency rule except",option:{a:"crisis",b:"blood lettings",c:"stage peaceful protest",d:"sabotage / terrorism"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:84,question:"Which of the following is not a function of political parties?",option:{a:"Aggregation of opinion",b:"Educating the government",c:"Interest articulation",d:"Unifying factor."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:279,question:"A sovereign state is one",option:{a:"whose citizens are free to evade responsibility",b:"whose governments decisions are made independent of foreign interference",c:"which has a president and a prime minister",d:"where its citizens can speak without fear or favour"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:16,question:"The division of Nigeria into various constituencies with each electing a person to represent it in the National Assembly is a demonstration of",option:{a:"checks and balances",b:"popular participation",c:"political rivalry among the constituents",d:"drive towards secession in the country."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:206,question:"The process of enlightening or training citizens on their rights and responsibilities is known as",option:{a:"Workshop training",b:"Citizenship Education",c:"Political Education",d:"Citizenship Rights"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:436,question:"From the above dialogue, political leaders can encourage citizens to perform their civic duties by",option:{a:"fulfilling their electoral promises",b:"travelling overseas to seek for foreign investors",c:"engaging in religious activities",d:"visiting all the local governments in the country"},section:"<strong>Zubar: </strong> Today is the day for gubernatorial elections, Ade what are you waiting for? Let us go and cast our votes for candidates of our choice<br><br> 	<strong>Ade: </strong> I have no interest in an election which not yield any dividend of democracy. Our political elite are only concerned about their interest when they get to the position 	of authority. For crying out loud, I have made up my mind that l will not vote again. <br><br> 	<strong>Zubar: </strong> Haba! Ade, don’t you remember Abraham Lincoln’s words that ‘all men are not just, all men are not true. But ...... for every scoundrel there is a hero, that for every selfish politician, there is a dedicated leader!’ Come on, go and cast your vote so that we can choose the right person for the position and change the political, economic and social directions of our great state.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:283,question:"Consumers of ......... especially ........... and ..............stand the a great risk of contacting the Ebola disease",option:{a:"fish, tilapia, titus",b:"bush meat, monkey, bat",c:"meat, cow, dog",d:"vegetable, water leaf, bitter leaf"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:68,question:"The National Youths Service Corps Scheme was established in Nigeria in",option:{a:"1970",b:"1971",c:"1973",d:"1975."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:49,question:"Cooperation between one country and another can be described as",option:{a:"bilateral",b:"international",c:"multilateral",d:"multinational."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:110,question:"The act of counting the numbers of people living in a country in order to determine the total numbers of 	people in a state is known as .......",option:{a:"election",b:"national population census",c:"voting",d:"rights"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:24,question:"The nearest government to the people and an important means of promoting grassroots development is the",option:{a:"state government",b:"unitary government",c:"local government",d:"federal government"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:87,question:"One of the following is a country as well as a continent.",option:{a:"Africa",b:"Antarctica",c:"Asia",d:"Australia"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:429,question:"Democracy is yet to take firm root in Africa because",option:{a:"it retards African development",b:"African leaders are not experienced enough",c:"most African leaders detest the will of the people",d:"it is an expensive system of government"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:165,question:"One of the main duties of the local government service commission is to",option:{a:"supervise and manage the personnel of local government",b:"conduct election into local council",c:"create an enabling working environment for council workers",d:"handle request for the creation of more local government"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:226,question:"The process of learning the political attitudes, values and beliefs that are relevant to the political system is known as",option:{a:"political culture",b:"political socialization",c:"political participation",d:"political science"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:424,question:"The foreign policy objective of Nigeria as enshrined in the 1999 Constitution exclude the promotion of",option:{a:"national interest",b:"African integration",c:"support for donor agencies",d:"just world economic order"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:143,question:"Motorcyclists must always protect their heads with safety ............. which must be properly fastened",option:{a:"seat belt",b:"head guild",c:"helmets",d:"cap cycles"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:29,question:"The implication of positive communal relationships is that it",option:{a:"promotes solidarity and love",b:"ensures obedience to constituted authority",c:"encourages ethnic diversity",d:"promotes rural-urban drift."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:262,question:"Vehicles are expected to continue with their journey when the traffic light shows ...............",option:{a:"Red",b:"Blue",c:"Yellow",d:"Green"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:435,question:"It could be inferred from the dialogue that failure to vote in an election would",option:{a:"guarantee citizens’ rights",b:"encourage the emergence of responsive government",c:"promote accountability in governance",d:"perpetuate irresponsible leadership"},section:"<strong>Zubar: </strong> Today is the day for gubernatorial elections, Ade what are you waiting for? Let us go and cast our votes for candidates of our choice<br><br> 	<strong>Ade: </strong> I have no interest in an election which not yield any dividend of democracy. Our political elite are only concerned about their interest when they get to the position 	of authority. For crying out loud, I have made up my mind that l will not vote again. <br><br> 	<strong>Zubar: </strong> Haba! Ade, don’t you remember Abraham Lincoln’s words that ‘all men are not just, all men are not true. But ...... for every scoundrel there is a hero, that for every selfish politician, there is a dedicated leader!’ Come on, go and cast your vote so that we can choose the right person for the position and change the political, economic and social directions of our great state.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:341,question:"The document containing the aims and programs of a political party is called ...........",option:{a:"register",b:"manifesto",c:"memorandum of party",d:"party library"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:338,question:"On the 18th of November 2014 in Yobe, some crowds lynched a suspected suicide bomber. The action of the crowd is .....",option:{a:"right because ‘he who kills by the sword must die by the sword’",b:"wrong because they have unlawfully taken the law into their hands, they should have handed the suicide  bomber over to the police",c:"right because we all have to fights against all forms of terrorism",d:"right so that others will learn lesson from this action"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:149,question:"The commission charged with the conduct of federal 	elections in Nigeria between 2014 and 2015 is..........",option:{a:"Nec",b:"fedeco",c:"Inec",d:"Necon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:1,question:"Who among the following could be described as the founding father of Nigerian nationalism?",option:{a:"Nnamdi Azikiwe",b:"Herbert Macauley",c:"Ahmadu Bello",d:"Obafemi Awolowo"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:219,question:"The use of illicit or hard drugs such as marijuana (Indian hemp) heroine, morphine etc. is known as",option:{a:"Human right abuse",b:"Drug trafficking",c:"Drug enhancement",d:"Drug abuse"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:145,question:"The former NAFDAC DG Prof Dora Akunyili died on",option:{a:"June 9. 2014",b:"June 17, 2014",c:"June 7, 2014",d:"May 27, 2014"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:223,question:"Which of the following constitutes drug abuse",option:{a:"taking less than the dose recommended by the doctor",b:"taking more than the dose recommended by the doctor",c:"taking the exact dose recommended by the doctor",d:"A and B above"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:348,question:"Lack of interest in politics by citizens in the country is referred to as political",option:{a:"ignorance",b:"apathy",c:"participation",d:"socialization"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:137,question:"When a group of people believe in and keep to certain norms, values and ways of life of their community since its creation, we call this .................",option:{a:"religion",b:"stereotypes",c:"traditions",d:"custom"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:317,question:"Which of these tax below is paid by nearly everybody in Nigeria",option:{a:"Direct tax",b:"Excise tax",c:"Proportional tax",d:"Regressive"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:261,question:"On a particular day in 2014, the National flag was flown half mask. This act symbolizes",option:{a:"National tailors day",b:"National mourning",c:"Children’s day",d:"Golden jubilee celebration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:79,question:"The public service structure of Nigeria is an offshoot of",option:{a:"America.",b:"British.",c:"Canada.",d:"India."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:20,question:"According to the story, Imoh’s parents were",option:{a:"wealthy couple",b:"prominent politicians",c:"honest and responsible",d:"religious fanatics"},section:"Imoh lived with her parents in Kakuri. They were good citizens who detested all forms of immoral acts. Both at home and in school, Imoh had been taught the virtues and values of a good citizen. However, while in a bus on her way home from school, the conductor forgot to ask for her fare. She knew that the right thing to do was to pay even when the conductor had forgotten to collect the fare. She also knew that there were other things she could do with the money if it was not paid, but she did what was expected by informing the conductor and paying the fare.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:378,question:"Children that are not cared for are mostly prone to",option:{a:"criminal attitudes",b:"terminal diseases",c:"examination failure",d:"forced migration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:114,question:"Cocaine, morphine and heroin are example of",option:{a:"tobacco",b:"steroids",c:"narcotics",d:"inhalants"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:281,question:"Juvenile delinquency refers to",option:{a:"active youths participation in sports",b:"wrong doings by the youths",c:"Refusal to worship God by the youths",d:"Urban Rural migration by the youth"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:25,question:"Democratic governance is usually characterized by",option:{a:"free, fair and credible elections",b:"buoyant and competitive economy",c:"accessible employment opportunities",d:"youth participation in governance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:146,question:"Political values are acquired in any given society through",option:{a:"Political re-orientation",b:"Political campaign",c:"Political socialization",d:"Political indoctrination"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:88,question:"In a parliamentary system of government, the powers of the executive is vested in the office of the",option:{a:"minister.",b:"premier",c:"president.",d:"prime minister."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:367,question:"Youth empowerment promotes",option:{a:"self-reliance",b:"youthful exuberance",c:"pursuit of higher education",d:"foreign scholarship"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:105,question:"Newspapers and magazine and example of ..... media",option:{a:"print",b:"electronic",c:"advertising",d:"mass"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:112,question:"The 219 chibok girls were ................ while ..............",option:{a:"abducted, praying in the mosque",b:"kidnaped, praying in the church",c:"abducted, wondering along the street of chibok town",d:"kidnaped, preparing to write their WAEC examination"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:263,question:"In which of the following system is survival of the fittest mostly practiced",option:{a:"Communist system",b:"Capitalist system",c:"Feudalist",d:"Totalistic system"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:200,question:"Which of the following is NOT an offence",option:{a:"Tax avoidance",b:"Tax evidence",c:"Stealing by trick",d:"Money laundering"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:320,question:"The former National anthem begins with.......................",option:{a:"Nigeria We Hail Thee",b:"Arise O Compatriots",c:"I pledge to Nigeria my Country",d:"So help me God"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:120,question:"One of the following is a cause of single parents in Nigeria",option:{a:"slow parenting",b:"social group",c:"nature of work",d:"divorce"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:361,question:"Drug abuse can be prevented by",option:{a:"fighting drug addicts",b:"poverty reduction",c:"reducing drugs in circulation",d:"legal sanction"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:73,question:"A political party’s programme is known as its",option:{a:"constitution.",b:"document.",c:"functions.",d:"manifesto."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:434,question:"Ade’s action as shown in the dialogue is a demonstration of political",option:{a:"wisdom",b:"apathy",c:"lawlessness",d:"participation"},section:"<strong>Zubar: </strong> Today is the day for gubernatorial elections, Ade what are you waiting for? Let us go and cast our votes for candidates of our choice<br><br> 	<strong>Ade: </strong> I have no interest in an election which not yield any dividend of democracy. Our political elite are only concerned about their interest when they get to the position 	of authority. For crying out loud, I have made up my mind that l will not vote again. <br><br> 	<strong>Zubar: </strong> Haba! Ade, don’t you remember Abraham Lincoln’s words that ‘all men are not just, all men are not true. But ...... for every scoundrel there is a hero, that for every selfish politician, there is a dedicated leader!’ Come on, go and cast your vote so that we can choose the right person for the position and change the political, economic and social directions of our great state.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:59,question:"The symbol for the campaign against AIDs is Ribbon",option:{a:"black",b:"blue",c:"green",d:"red"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:298,question:"Which of the following is not a preventive measure against the acquisition of the Ebola disease...........",option:{a:"Do not touch an infected person or their body fluids including blood, vomit, urine, saliva",b:"Wash your hands regularly with soap and water and apply sanitizers frequently",c:"Beware of hand shake and go for medical checkup as soon as possible when sick",d:"Do not bath with medicated soap"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:313,question:"In Lagos state, the BRT lane is reserved for ....... only",option:{a:"The governor",b:"Soldiers",c:"Commercial buses",d:"BRT buses"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:314,question:"Mondays and Thursday are days meant for in between environmental sanitation exercise in ........... and .......... states respectively",option:{a:"Lagos and Edo",b:"Edo and Lagos",c:"Abuja and Lagos",d:"Delta and Lagos"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:421,question:"Association and affiliation between two or more people is called",option:{a:"multilateral relations",b:"bilateral relations",c:"inter-communal relations",d:"interpersonal relations"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:395,question:"The National Agency for Food and Drug Administration and Control (NAFDAC) was established in",option:{a:"1993",b:"1996",c:"1999",d:"2001"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:273,question:"The attitude of the crowd towards, the sick man was that of ............",option:{a:"indifference",b:"friendliness",c:"hospitality",d:"political apathy"},section:"A certain man came to visit his friend at Shomolu one early morning. Unexpectedly the man fainted and slumped. He lay on the floor for several hours and looking lifeless. The crowd and even the friend he came to visit kept a reasonable distance from him. No one came to his rescue or even attempted to touch him. As luck would have it he regained his strength after about five hours and managed to go back to his house",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:343,question:"Orderliness can be defined as",option:{a:"being punctual to work",b:"studying diligently in school",c:"doing things in a proper way",d:"learning the Western way of life"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:275,question:"If the crowd insisted on keeping their distance what appropriate action could they have taken",option:{a:"call the appropriate health department to intervene",b:"left him to his fate",c:"stone him to death",d:"desert him"},section:"A certain man came to visit his friend at Shomolu one early morning. Unexpectedly the man fainted and slumped. He lay on the floor for several hours and looking lifeless. The crowd and even the friend he came to visit kept a reasonable distance from him. No one came to his rescue or even attempted to touch him. As luck would have it he regained his strength after about five hours and managed to go back to his house",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:108,question:"The form of government in which the electorate exercise their governing power directly through their elected 	representation is called ........",option:{a:"supremacy",b:"democracy",c:"autocracy",d:"charismatic"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:331,question:"Those eligible to partake in the scheme are those",option:{a:"Those seeking for admission into the higher institutions",b:"Who have successfully completed their studies from higher institution .eg. college of education, 		     polytechnic & university",c:"Who are looking for something to keep them busy",d:"Who are from poor family background"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:299,question:"Nigeria celebrated her centenary anniversary in the ......",option:{a:"1954",b:"1960",c:"1963",d:"2014"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:10,question:"Victims of human trafficking are usually compelled to engage in",option:{a:"lucrative employment",b:"visiting tourist sites",c:"part - time studies",d:"forced labour."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:60,question:"ln 2013, Nigeria celebrated her ______ independence anniversary",option:{a:"50th",b:"51st",c:"52nd",d:"54th"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:419,question:"The above quotation summarizes the",option:{a:"Universal Declaration of Human Rights.",b:"African Charter on Human Rights.",c:"Geneva Conventions and Protocols.",d:"United Nations Organization Charter."},section:"“All human beings are born free and equal in dignity and rights. They are endowed with reason and 		conscience and should act towards one another in a spirit of brotherhood”.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:268,question:"Political Apathy can lead to",option:{a:"very fast pace of development",b:"the emergence of sound democratic government",c:"wrong set of people coming into power",d:"development of sound political culture"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:9,question:"It could be inferred from the statements above that cultism in schools could lead to",option:{a:"sudden prosperity.",b:"uninterrupted academic calender.",c:"popularity on campus.",d:"untimely death."},section:"NEWS: ‘Rival Cult Group Killed Ten on Campus’<br> 	STUDENT: I will definitely need a bullet proof vest before I can go back to the Campus.<br>",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:107,question:"The following are duties to be performed by the citizens of a country EXCEPT",option:{a:"Destroying government properties",b:"obey law and order",c:"payment of tax",d:"show loyalty"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:396,question:"National Agency for the Prohibition of Traffic in Persons (NAPTIP) is an initiative of",option:{a:"Federal Government of Nigeria",b:"United States Agency for International Development",c:"Woman Trafficking and Child Labour Eradication 	Foundation",d:"United Nations Office on Drugs and Crime"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:296,question:"Public servants in Nigeria are expected to be .............",option:{a:"involved in politics",b:"non-partisan",c:"ambitious politically",d:"partial"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:169,question:"The term V. I. O. mean",option:{a:"Vehicle inspection officer",b:"vehicle implementation officer",c:"vehicle induce operation",d:"vehicle induction officer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:267,question:"The right practice of democracy can",option:{a:"ensure equity, justice and far play",b:"discourage political education and awareness’",c:"political unrest",d:"lawlessness"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:94,question:"When the national flag is flown half mask, it is a sign of national",option:{a:"centenary celebration",b:"children’s day",c:"independence",d:"mourning"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:289,question:"That which people enjoy primarily because they are human beings are called ...............",option:{a:"Human Obligation",b:"Constitutional Right",c:"Human Right",d:"Democratic Right"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:303,question:"As at 2014 Nigeria has .......... states",option:{a:"47",b:"37",c:"60",d:"57"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:228,question:"It is an offense to drive along the high way",option:{a:"without putting on the seat belt",b:"and talk or smile at the same time",c:"and make phone calls at the same time",d:"A and C above"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:34,question:"The most popular means through which citizens of a country can participate in politics is by",option:{a:"being members of political parties",b:"engaging in constructive criticism",c:"engaging in political debates",d:"voting in elections"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:248,question:"The primary function of the legislature is the",option:{a:"monitoring the executive",b:"making of laws",c:"voting of bills",d:"appointment of ministers"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:178,question:"All type of government perform all the following functions except",option:{a:"providing welfare and developmental facilities",b:"maintaining law and order",c:"encouraging the struggle for power",d:"encouraging trade with other state"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:77,question:"One advantage of Bi-cameral legislature is that it",option:{a:"guards against intra-party clashes.",b:"is the only system available.",c:"prevents arbitrary law making",d:"projects party manifestoes."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:325,question:"A committee of PDP members is made up of 9 Hausas, 8 Igbo and 7 Yorubas. If the president wishes to choose just one person to be his special adviser, find the probability that the person chosen is neither Hausa nor Yoruba",option:{a:"7/24",b:"2/3",c:"3/8",d:"1/3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:311,question:"Another word for abduction is ...........................",option:{a:"to steal",b:"to adopt",c:"to kidnap",d:"to kill"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:233,question:"The principle of equality before the law is the same as",option:{a:"social equality",b:"social injustices",c:"checks and balances",d:"democratic justices"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:411,question:"Which of the following statements best describes Human Trafficking?",option:{a:"Recruitment of youths as casual workers",b:"Desperate desire by youths to travel abroad",c:"Buying and selling of humans for selfish purposes",d:"Transportation of gods and service through human portage"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:65,question:"When was the first HIV/AIDs case reported in Nigeria?",option:{a:"1980",b:"1983",c:"1985",d:"1987"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:270,question:"During a particular voting exercise if majority of the 	people refuse to vote, this can be described as",option:{a:"political stubbornness",b:"political apathy",c:"political awareness",d:"political socialization"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:207,question:"The ideas, things or principles cherished by the people in a community are referred to as",option:{a:"rights",b:"culture",c:"values",d:"due process"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:249,question:"Ejiro, the senior brother of Omonigho had fever last week. The doctor prescribed a certain drug for him, He was asked to take one tablet, three times a day for four days. He took the drug as recommend for the first and second day and stopped. Five days later he took one tablet in the morning and one again at night. Omonigho’s action can be said to be a kind of",option:{a:"bad drug administration",b:"drug Abuse",c:"drug trafficking",d:"Human trafficking"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:394,question:"The following cadre of students are the main target for campus cult membership except",option:{a:"students from wealthy homes",b:"students from influential parents",c:"bold and morally sound students",d:"wayward and fun-loving students"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:180,question:"Which of the following is an advantage of local government",option:{a:"Agents for money based politics",b:"electoral commissions",c:"training grounds for political leaders",d:"agents of pressure group"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:334,question:"Which of the following is true",option:{a:"The CD (Community Development) exercise   embarked by corpers is not paid for by the community",b:"Corpers collect extra money for embarking on the C.D",c:"Corpers are not usually given monthly allowances",d:"The aim of the NYSC scheme is to foster disunity   in the country"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:316,question:"Which of the following is the cleanest source of water in Nigeria",option:{a:"pond water",b:"river water",c:"rain water",d:"lagoon water"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:373,question:"Which of the following is not a form of political participation?",option:{a:"Taking part in voters’ registration exercise",b:"Voting during elections",c:"Joining political party",d:"Ballot box stuffing during elections"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:392,question:"Two forms of road signs are regulatory and",option:{a:"punitive",b:"informative",c:"persuasive",d:"inhibitive"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:288,question:"Through which of these can citizenship status be acquired",option:{a:"birth, naturalization, honorary and registration",b:"birth, colonization and integration",c:"referendum, incorporation and acceptance",d:"convention registration and colonization"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:66,question:"Which of the following system of government advocates equitable distribution of wealth?",option:{a:"Aristocracy",b:"Capitalism",c:"Plutocracy",d:"Socialism"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:364,question:"Cult members are particularly hostile to",option:{a:"lecturers",b:"perceived enemies",c:"their group members",d:"all students"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:181,question:"Public Corporations are financed",option:{a:"by tax payers",b:"with private funds",c:"with entrepreneurial funds",d:"by political parties"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:199,question:"The law is enforced by",option:{a:"Military",b:"Legislators",c:"Police force",d:"Area boys"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"}],n={message:e,subject:o,status:200,total:120,data:a};export{a as data,n as default,e as message,i as status,o as subject,t as total};
